(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
hololive Summer 2022
Climax Story Live
ホロライブサマー2022…、最後のフィナーレはライブの開催です！
hololive Summer 2022... the final finale is the holding of a live concert!
この夏は 何度も 夢見た渚の宝物
This summer is a treasure on the shore I've dreamed of many times
Shiny Smile
Smile Your Heart
Heart To Heart
Oh Yeah!
せーのっ
Ready, go!
びえん ぱおん はにゃっ
Bien, Paon, Hanya!
お待たせっ！
Thanks for waiting!
さーままさまさまさま あっちっちーの「さまー」
Sa-mama-sama-sama-sama, hot "summer"
さーままさまさまさま ぴっちぴち「さまー」
Sa-mama-sama-sama-sama, lively "summer"
いーけいけ「さまー」 いーちゃいちゃ「さまー」
Go-go "summer", flirtatious "summer"
女神さま
Goddess
Foo~~~~~~!!
(A!) ええ 湘南の空に白い雲 そして
(A!) Yes, white clouds in the Shonan sky, and
(B!) ビーチ砂浜これこれこのムード
(B!) Beach, sandy shore, this is the mood
(素晴らC!) 史上最強の私がヴィーナス
(Wonderful C!) The strongest me in history is a Venus
一番なんて決めらんない
I can't decide who's number one
「それな？」
"Right?"
(D!) どこで買ったのその水着？ めっちゃいい
(D!) Where'd you buy that swimsuit? It's so nice
「いいですね～」「いいですね～」
"It's nice~" "It's nice~"
煩悩 お空へ飛んでっK！
Desires, fly away to the sky!
経験豊富な私たちでも
Even for us with plenty of experience
至らない境地 それが
There's a level we haven't reached, that's...
ホロライブサマー！
hololive Summer!
パラソル ビチェア この時間フォーエバー
Parasols, beach chairs, this time forever
君も隣くる？
Will you come next to me too?
きたきたきたきた！ ビーチの1級建築士
Here it comes! 1st class beach architect
波打ち際にキャッスル新築 (Ha!)
Newly built castle on the shore (Ha!)
もっと はしゃぎ過ぎたくなって
I want to frolic even more
「その目に焼き付けるおぉぉい！！！」
"Searing it into those eyes!!!"
Yeah~~~~!!
この夏は (ハイ！) 何度も (ハイ！)
This summer (Hi!) many times (Hi!)
夢見た渚の宝物
Treasure on the shore I've dreamed of
Shiny Smile (う～Shiny Smile)
Shiny Smile (Ooh~ Shiny Smile)
飛沫あげて (ハイ！) 弾けて (ハイ！)
Splashing (Hi!) popping (Hi!)
また笑って (ヤー！)
And laughing again (Ya!)
裸足で描いてる Story
Drawing a story barefoot
泳いで (FuFu) 泳いで (FuFu)
Swimming (FuFu) swimming (FuFu)
その先へ (せーのっ)
Beyond that (Ready, go!)
びえん ぱおん はにゃっ
Bien, Paon, Hanya!
はぴはぴっ
Hapi Hapi!
さーままさまさまさま あっちっちーの「さまー」
Sa-mama-sama-sama-sama, hot "summer"
さーままさまさまさま ぴっちぴち「さまー」
Sa-mama-sama-sama-sama, lively "summer"
いーけいけ「さまー」 いーちゃいちゃ「さまー」
Go-go "summer", flirtatious "summer"
女神さま
Goddess
Foo~~~~~~!!
(ワン！) 水着の柄を褒めるべし～
(One!) You should praise the pattern of my swimsuit~
(ツー！) 海の魔物から守るべし～
(Two!) You should protect me from sea monsters~
(スリー！) 他の子は見ちゃヤダヤダヤダー
(Three!) Don't look at other girls, no no no
一番だって言ってよね
Say I'm number one, okay?
「よっしゃー！」
"Alright!"
煌めく肌と (肌と) ギラギラサンセット (サンセット)
Sparkling skin (skin) and dazzling sunset (sunset)
お待ちかねボンファイヤー！
The long-awaited bonfire!
きたきたきたきた！ パーティー開催午後六時
Here it comes! Party starts at 6 PM
ドレスコードは日焼けのアート
Dress code is tan line art
空に 花火打ち上がって
Fireworks go up in the sky
「パーティーの始まりだぁぁぁ！！！！」
"The party is starting!!!!"
（カンパーーーイ！）
Cheers!
この夏も (ハイ！) いつかは (ハイ！)
This summer too (Hi!) someday (Hi!)
キラめく思い出になるよね
Will become a sparkling memory, right?
Shooting Star (う～Shooting Star)
Shooting Star (Ooh~ Shooting Star)
声をあげて (ハイ！) 願えば (ハイ！)
Raise your voice (Hi!) and if you wish (Hi!)
ほら 叶うよ (ヤー！)
Look, it'll come true (Ya!)
神様だって 見惚れちゃう
Even God would be captivated
たわわで (FuFu) はわわな (FuFu)
Lush (FuFu) and fluttery (FuFu)
パラダイス
Paradise
せーのっ
Ready, go!
びえん ぱおん はにゃっ
Bien, Paon, Hanya!
どきどきっ
Doki Doki!
これこそが！ YES！ ホロライブサマー！！
This is it! YES! hololive Summer!!
(ホロライブサマー！！)
(hololive Summer!!)
最高の景色 そして
The best scenery, and
きゃわわなヴィーナス
Cute Venus
骨の髄まで遊び尽くせーー！！
Play to the marrow of your bones!!
ビーチバレーいくわよ～！ おらぁ！ ジャスティス！
Beach volleyball, let's go! Oraa! Justice!
(Wow Wow Wow Wow) ～ 爆メシ 爆メシ 限りなし おし！
(Wow Wow Wow Wow) ~ Explosive meal, explosive meal, endless, oshi!
(Wow Wow Wow Wow) ～ ジェットスキーでバナナボートにキック！
(Wow Wow Wow Wow) ~ Kick the banana boat with a jet ski!
(Wow Wow Wow Wow) ～ 負けたらチョメチョメ王様ゲーム！
(Wow Wow Wow Wow) ~ If you lose, chome-chome King's Game!
(Wow Wow Wow Wow) ～ 覗いちゃダメ！
(Wow Wow Wow Wow) ~ No peeking!
岩場の陰でお着替え (あんっ)
Changing behind the rocks (An!)
乙女の秘密は ハラドキハラドキハラドキハラドキ
A maiden's secret is heart-pounding heart-pounding...
いやぁぁ～～～ん！
Nooooo!
黄昏の浜辺で
On the beach at dusk
背中合わせた合言葉は
The password we whispered back to back
I Need You (I Need You)
(I Need You) (I Need You)
波の音が
The sound of waves...
痺れさせる
...sends shivers.
火照った身体
My heated body...
ドキドキ もう止まんないね
...my heart won't stop throbbing.
真夏の奇跡 (真夏の奇跡)
A midsummer miracle (A midsummer miracle)
ちゅわちゅわ ちゅわちゅわ ちゅー
Chuwachuwa chuwachuwa chuu
この声も (ハイ!)
Even this voice (Hey!)
想いも (ハイ!)
Even these feelings (Hey!)
夢見た渚の宝物
Treasures on the beach I dreamed of
Shiny Smile (う〜 Shiny Smile)
Shiny Smile (Ooh~ Shiny Smile)
時を止めて (ハイ!)
Stop time (Hey!)
みんなで (ハイ!)
Everyone together (Hey!)
また笑って (ヤー!)
Let's laugh again (Yeah!)
裸足で描いた ハートマーク
A heart mark drawn with bare feet
歌って (FuFu)
Sing (FuFu)
遊んで (FuFu)
Play (FuFu)
その先へ
To what lies ahead...
ぴえん ぱおん ぱにゃ さまさまで〜す♡
Pien Paon Panya Samasama〜♡
「最高の夏にしようねっ」
"Let's make this the best summer!"
この海で
At this sea
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our new-born heartbeats resound
最高の時間 最高の仲間と きらめきに乗って
A wonderful time with wonderful friends, riding on the glitter
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider
覚えてるかな 最初(はじ)めての歌
Do you remember? Our first song...
懐かしいね
How nostalgic.
少し声が震えていた ほんの少し
Our voices were shaking, just a little bit
あの日から続く未来は みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
The future continuing from that day is the today we grasped with everyone
もっともっともっと 加速するハート
More, more, more, our hearts accelerate
一緒に行くよ どこまでも (Are you ready?)
We'll go together everywhere (Are you ready?)
準備はOK!
Ready to go!
開け 夢の扉を 1, 2, 3!
Open the door of dreams! 1, 2, 3!
キラメキライダー
Kirameki Rider
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our new-born heartbeats resound
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
A wonderful time with wonderful friends
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here because you found me
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
I came here because I wanted to see you, let's all sing
終わらないメロディ キラメキにのって
The endless melody, riding on the glitter
届いてるかな 私の声 はっきりと
Is my voice reaching you clearly?
届けたいのは君に笑顔 そのスマイル
What I want to deliver to you is a smile, that smile
いっそのこと一生の 宝物にしようって
Let's make it a lifelong treasure
みんなと泣き笑ったね
We cried and laughed together
ぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっと 全て抱きしめて
Tightly, tightly, tightly, embracing everything
一緒に行こう どこまでも (Are you ready?)
Let's go together everywhere (Are you ready?)
準備はOK!
Ready to go!
進め 希望の道を 1, 2, 3!
March on the path of hope! 1, 2, 3!
キラメキライダー
Kirameki Rider
素敵な気持ち カラフルに奏でたいな
I want to play these wonderful feelings in full color
最高の場所 最高ののみんなと
At the best place with the best people
ここにいるよ 幻の歌じゃない
I'm right here, it's not an illusory song
君の心が幸せに染まるよう
Hoping your heart is dyed with happiness
重なってくハーモニー キラメキまとって
The overlapping harmony, wearing the glitter
歌い続けたいな
I want to keep singing
踊り続けたいな
I want to keep dancing
そんな願いやわがままも いいでしょ?
Such wishes and selfishness are fine, right?
だって楽しすぎて 止まらない
Because it's so fun that I can't stop
輝くステージでもっともっと
On the shining stage, more and more
お願い ずっと...
Please, forever...
居るよ　私ここに居るよ
I'm here, I'm right here
君と同じ世界を　見つめていてよ
Looking at the same world as you
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats resound
最高の時間　最高の仲間と
The best time with the best friends
ここに居るよ　見つけてくれたから
I'm here because you found me
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ　みんなで歌おう
I came here because I wanted to see you, let's all sing
せーの！終わらないメロディ
Ready, go! The never-ending melody
キラメキに乗って
Ride on the sparkle
キラメキ纏って
Adorned in sparkle
イェーイ！
Yeah!
はい、ということで！
Yes, and so!
こんばんは！
Good evening!
本日はホロライブサマー2022の最後を飾るライブ、
Today is the live performance that marks the end of Hololive Summer 2022,
クライマックスストーリーライブを見に来てくれて、みんなありがとう！
thank you all for coming to see the Climax Story Live!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
公式チャンネルでやるライブということでね、僕たちのことを知らない人もいると思うから、
Since this live is on the official channel, there might be people who don't know us,
最初に自己紹介しておきましょうか。
so let's start with some self-introductions.
おっけーまる！
Okay-maru!
じゃ、僕からいきますね。はい。
Then I'll go first. Yes.
いくよ！
Here I go!
もぐもぐー！おかゆー！
Mogu mogu! Okayu!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです。
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers.
今日はいっぱい楽しんでくださいね！
Please enjoy yourselves to the fullest today!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ハーローボー！
Hello-bo!
ポン、ヤヤ、高性能バーチャルロボットの、AZKiだよ！
Pon, yaya, high-performance virtual robot, AZKi here!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
みんな楽しんどるかー？
Is everyone having fun?
楽しんどるー！
We're having fun!
じゃあ次はー？
Next up?
はい！皆さん、こんまっする！
Yes! Everyone, Kon-muscle!
ホロライブ三期生の脳筋女騎士こと、白銀ノエルです！
I'm Shirogane Noel, the muscle-brained female knight of Hololive's 3rd generation!
いやー今日はめちゃめちゃ楽しむぞー！
Man, I'm going to have so much fun today!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
はい、ということで僕たち三人がキラメキライダーをお送りしました！
Yes, so the three of us performed "Kirameki Rider"!
お送りしましたー！
We did!
いやー、僕たちこの三人はね、ふわふわっと漂う感じのキラメキライダーになったんじゃないでしょうか。
I think the three of us gave "Kirameki Rider" a sort of fluffy, floating feel.
ふわふわしとった。
It was fluffy.
ふわふわしとったねー。
It really was fluffy.
一曲目もね、皆さん、見ましたか？
And did everyone see the first song too?
見ましたかー？
Did you?
見たー！もうなんか元気だった！
I saw it! It was so energetic!
ねー、すごかったよね。
Yeah, it was amazing.
新曲の「飛んでK！ホロライブサマー」は、ライブ初公開ということで、最初から飛ばしてたね。
The new song "Tonde K! Hololive Summer" was performed for the first time live, and it was full throttle from the start.
ねー。
Yeah.
A-B-C-D...ってやってて、めちゃめちゃ可愛かった！
The A-B-C-D part was so cute!
めちゃめちゃ可愛かったねー。
It was super cute.
あ、あ、待って。
Ah, wait.
なに？
What?
団長！
Danchou!
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
いや、ちょっと忘れてることある。みんなも忘れてない？
Well, I think we're forgetting something. Aren't you all forgetting something too?
待て待て。
Wait, wait.
なにー？
What?
ホロライブサマーと言ったら、水着！ですよ！
When you think of Hololive Summer, you think of swimsuits!
水着でダンスするのは、公式では今回初公開なの！
This is the first time we've performed a dance in swimsuits on the official channel!
おー、なるほど！
Oh, I see!
すごいね。
That's amazing.
じゃあせっかくだしね、見てる人にこの僕たちの姿をね、見てもらいましょうか。
Then, since we're here, let's let the viewers have a good look at us.
見て見てー！
Look, look!
じゃあちょっと、一緒にピースなんかしてみますか。
Then, shall we strike a peace sign together?
ピース！あ、いいねー。
Peace! Ah, nice.
アイドルっぽい。
So idol-like.
アイドルっぽいよね。はい、チーズ！
It is idol-like. Ready, smile!
はい。イェーイ、可愛いー！
Yes. Yay, so cute!
え、ちょっと近づいちゃったりして。
Oh, maybe I'll get a little closer.
おー！みんなスクショ撮ってさ、思い出でツイートしてねー。
Oh! Everyone, take screenshots and tweet them as memories.
みんな撮っとるかー？
Is everyone taking them?
可愛いー。
So cute.
可愛いねー。
It's cute.
じゃあ、さて皆さん、満足してくれたかな？
So, everyone, are you satisfied?
満足してくれたかにょ？
Are you satisfied-nyo?
そろそろね、次の曲に行かないとなんですが。
It's almost time to move on to the next song.
最後に、みんなはホロライブサマーのストーリーは追ってくれたのかな？
Finally, did everyone follow the Hololive Summer story?
あー、そうだね、ストーリーがありました。
Ah, that's right, there was a story.
まだ追ってない人はもうこのライブが終わった後にバーッと追ってください！
If you haven't followed it yet, please binge it after this live!
お願いします、バーッと。
Please do, binge it.
ね、追いつけるからね。ぜひぜひチェックしてくれよな。
Yeah, you can catch up. Be sure to check it out.
要チェック！
Check it out!
ということでね、そろそろ時間が来たので、次の曲行ってみましょうか。
And so, since it's about time, shall we move on to the next song?
おっけーまる！
Okay-maru!
クライマックスストーリーライブはまだまだ続くので、皆さんぜひ最後まで見てくださいね。
The Climax Story Live is still going, so please watch until the end.
お願いしまーす。
Please do.
続いての曲はー？
The next song is...?
こちらー！
This one!
少しずつ
Little by little,
近づいて
I'm getting closer,
いるよ 夢に見たときめき
to the excitement I saw in my dreams.
広がってく 世界中に
Spreading throughout the world,
みんなを笑顔にさせるきらめきも
even the sparkle that makes everyone smile.
一人全部じゃないんだ
I'm not doing it all alone,
仲間がいるから
because I have my friends.
きっと言い合う言葉
The words we say to each other
楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
will surely become fun.
BE MY PRAY!
未来へ走り出したらファンタジー
If we run toward the future, it's a fantasy.
夢を咲かせて OUR FUTURE
Let our dreams bloom, OUR FUTURE.
一歩一歩踏み出して
Taking it step by step,
遠くを目指そう
let's aim for the distance.
信じる力が心のハピネス
The power to believe is the heart's happiness.
全力で楽しもう
Let's enjoy it with all our might.
それはいつかきっと
One day, it will surely
大きな夢叶えるから
make our big dreams come true.
Dreaming Days
答えのない道をゆく
Traveling down a road without answers,
誰も見たことのない世界
into a world no one has ever seen.
触れていくよ みんなのこと
I'll get in touch with everyone.
覚悟はいいかな
Are you ready?
手を離さないで
Don't let go of my hand.
一人じゃないから
Because you're not alone,
君が見ているから
because you are watching.
はじめての挑戦も
Even our first challenge
楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
will become fun.
STEP BY STEP!
YEAH!
奇跡を巻き起こすんだ GLORIA
Let's spark a miracle, GLORIA.
夢に近づいて MY STORY
Getting closer to my dream, MY STORY.
とても小さな蕾が
Until a very small bud
花咲かせるまで
comes into full bloom.
挑戦し続けるんだ BRILLIANT
I'll keep on challenging, BRILLIANT.
全力で飛び込もう
Let's jump in with all our might.
ほんの少しだけの
Just a tiny bit
勇気が今
of courage now
芽生えたんだ
has begun to sprout.
Dreaming Days
選んできた 未来の選択肢
The future choices I've made,
全てがほら 私を作った
they are all what made me who I am.
選ぶことのなかった答え
The answers I didn't choose,
大事な意味があったと気づいたよ
I realized they had an important meaning.
涙を流した数 エモーション
The number of tears I shed is emotion.
熱い心がオーバーヒート
My passionate heart is overheating.
本気だからこそ燃える
I'm burning precisely because I'm serious.
トップになりたい
I want to be at the top!
未来へ走り出したらファンタジー
If we run toward the future, it's a fantasy.
全力で楽しもう
Let's enjoy it with all our might.
それはいつかきっと
One day, it will surely
大きな夢叶えるから
make our big dreams come true.
Dreaming Days
OH YEAH!
走り続けていくんだ BRAVE
I'll keep on running, BRAVE.
一人で届かない高みへ
To a height I can't reach alone!
BLUE CLAPPER
手を上げて CLAP YOUR HANDS 海の向こうまで
Put your hands up, CLAP YOUR HANDS, to the other side of the ocean!
CLAP YOUR HANDS 届きますように
CLAP YOUR HANDS, may they reach you!
手を叩こう！
Let's clap our hands!
ほら一緒に！
Come on, let's do it together!
EVERYBODY CLAP YOUR HANDS 空の向こうまで
EVERYBODY CLAP YOUR HANDS, to the other side of the sky!
CLAP YOUR HANDS 響きますように
CLAP YOUR HANDS, may they echo through!
手を叩こう！
Let's clap our hands!
光射す 僕たちの未来
Our future, shining with light!
いこう！
Let's go!
HOLOLIVE 5 STARS!
始めようか STUDY
Shall we begin, STUDY?
待っても意味ない TIMING
No point in waiting, TIMING.
あの魚みたいに SWIMMING SWIMMING
Like those fish, SWIMMING SWIMMING.
引き寄せるの RIGHTY
Drawing it closer, RIGHTY.
まだ見えない MERRY
Still out of sight, MERRY.
この先には何があるの？
What lies ahead?
まだ早い...
It's too soon...
取り寄せて
Get it ready
美味しくマジェスティック
Tasty and majestic
眠っても醒めても シンキングシンキング
Whether asleep or awake, thinking, thinking
変えてみせる展示
I'll change the display
踏み出すワンステップ
Taking a first step
掴んでみせるよ キラキラ
I'll grab it, sparkling
マジ かなう日までストーリー 繋ぐ心
Truly, a story until the day it comes true, connecting hearts
さあ君に ずっと見てほしいから
Now, because I want you to keep watching
手をあげて Clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands, clap your hands, to the other side of the sea
Clap your hands 音届きますように
Clap your hands, hoping the sound reaches you
手をたたこう 手をたたこう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら一緒に
Look, all together
Everybody Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Everybody clap your hands, to the other side of the sky
Clap your hands 響き渡りますように
Clap your hands, hoping it echoes all around
手をたたこう 手をたたこう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
光射す僕たちの未来
Light shining on our future
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
今日は要らないブレーキ
No need for brakes today
一斉号砲はステイキング
The simultaneous starting signal is staking
何時でもいいでしょう 四六時中
Any time is fine, all day and night
君は何をフィーリング
What are you feeling?
解き放つスパークリング
Releasing the sparkling
暗闇に放つレーザービーム
Releasing a laser beam into the darkness
輝かせてステージ 作るから
I'll make the stage shine
さあ君に もっと見てほしいから
Now, because I want you to watch even more
手をあげて Clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands, clap your hands, to the other side of the sea
Clap your hands 音届きますように
Clap your hands, hoping the sound reaches you
手をたたこう 手をたたこう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら一緒に
Look, all together
Everybody Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Everybody clap your hands, to the other side of the sky
Clap your hands 響き渡りますように
Clap your hands, hoping it echoes all around
手をたたこう 手をたたこう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
重なるウェーブ 世界を揺らせ
Overlapping waves, shake the world
DJ POLKA Yo!
DJポルカここに参上
DJ Polka is here
盛り上がってけ この最上
Get excited, this is the best
愛をもっとくらわそう
Let's give even more love
上を向いてぶち上がろうぜ
Look up and let's go crazy
不安があることくらい既に I know
I already know that there's anxiety
でもまだまだ泳ぎ足りないな
But I still haven't swum enough
Give me crazy まるでLazy
Give me crazy, just like lazy
次元混ざり合うのすべて塗り替えるBLUE
Dimensions mixing, repaint everything BLUE
手をあげて Clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands, clap your hands, to the other side of the sea
Clap your hands 音届きますように
Clap your hands, hoping the sound reaches you
手をたたこう 手をたたこう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら一緒に
Look, all together
Everybody Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Everybody clap your hands, to the other side of the sky
Clap your hands 響き渡りますように
Clap your hands, hoping it echoes all around
手をたたこう 手をたたこう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
光射す僕たちの未来
Light shining on our future
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
はーい！ということで！ イエーイ！
Alright! Here we go! Yay!
コンネネ、コンポル、コンラミ、コンばんわんだばだー！イエーイ！
Kon-Nene, Kon-Pol, Kon-Lamy, Kon-Banwandabada! Yay!
ホロライブ・サマー2022、みんな楽しんでるかーい！？
Hololive Summer 2022, is everyone having fun!?
楽しんでるかーい！？ 楽しんでるかーい！？
Are you having fun!? Are you having fun!?
もっともっと声出して、もっともっと声出して！はいはいはいはい！
Speak up more, speak up more! Yes yes yes yes!
はい！公式チャンネルということでね、簡単に自己紹介していきましょう。
Alright! Since we're on the official channel, let's do some quick introductions.
はい、ねぽらぼの「ね」からいきましょう。
Alright, let's start from the "Ne" of NePoLaBo.
はーい！ねぽらぼの「ね」、桃鈴ねねです！
Haaai! The "Ne" of NePoLaBo, Momosuzu Nene here!
はい！ねぽらぼの「ぽ」、尾丸ポルカです！よろしくお願いします！
Alright! The "Po" of NePoLaBo, Omaru Polka here! Nice to meet you!
はい！ねぽらぼの「ら」、雪花ラミィです！よろしくお願いします！
Alright! The "La" of NePoLaBo, Yukihana Lamy here! Nice to meet you!
はい！ねぽらぼの「ぼ」、獅白ぼたんです！
Alright! The "Bo" of NePoLaBo, Shishiro Botan here!
ということで、はい、私たちで『BLUE CLAPPER』をお送りしましたー！
And with that, yes, we performed "BLUE CLAPPER"!
どうだったー！？これもう絶対盛り上がる！私たちが歌って盛り上がらないわけがない！
How was it!? This is definitely exciting! There's no way it wouldn't be exciting when we sing it!
盛り上がらなかったことはない！これを私たちが歌って盛り上がらないわけがない！んだよねー！
It's never not been exciting! There's no way it wouldn't be exciting when we sing it! Right!
あ、でもその前に、えーっとうちらが歌った前にドリーミングデイズ組が歌ってたやん。
Ah, but before that, um, before we sang, the Dreaming Days group was singing.
よかったねー、先輩たち可愛かったねー！
That was great, the seniors were so cute!
あの可愛いのね、あのちょこ先がちょっと先生だからさ本当に。練習の時もさ先生がさ、こうやって。
That cuteness, Choco-sen is really like a teacher. Even during practice, the teacher was like this.
「みんな、ハイ！」みたいな感じでやってた。
She was doing things like, "Everyone, high!"
マジでめちゃくちゃ可愛かったわ。
It was seriously so cute.
可愛かった〜。
ねえ、すごいダンスも可愛かったし。
So cute~
Yeah, the dance was really cute too.
シオン先輩がすごい可愛かった。
Shion-senpai was so cute.
ねえ、ちょこちょこ、ちょこちょこして。
Yeah, those little pitter-patter movements.
ねえ、ちょこちょこした動きがさ、ちょっとさ、
身長低い組とスレンダーなちょこ先だとさ、
Those little movements, you know...
and between the short group and slender Choco-sen,
全然差が出てて可愛かった。
there was a total contrast and it was so cute.
ねえ、でもシオン先輩キレッキレで好き。
Yeah, but I loved how sharp Shion-senpai was.
ねえ、キレッキレだった！
Yeah, she was so sharp!
はい、じゃあうちらも。
Okay, then we should also...
あ、そうだね！
Oh, that's right!
アピールタイムする？アピールタイムね！
Shall we do some appeal time? Appeal time!
何しよ？え、何するの？
What should we do? Eh, what are we doing?
ちょっと、ねねが得意なんじゃない？
スクショタイムみたいなのいっちゃいますか？
Wait, isn't Nene good at this?
Shall we do something like a screenshot time?
上手いね、ねね！上手い！イェーイ！
You're good at this, Nene! So good! Yay!
え、ちょっとやっぱみんなこれやりたいよね？
Eh, wait, everyone wants to do this, right?
え、ちょっとまずこれで固まろうよ。
Eh, let's first strike a pose like this.
なんかバレーボールみたいになってない？
Doesn't this look like volleyball?
違う、レシーブ！レシーブ返し！
No, it's a receive! A counter-receive!
もういいから、いいから！次はダンス！時間！時間！
Enough already! Next is the dance! Time! Time!
時間ちょっと出してもらって！バッチリ決めて！
Give us a little more time! Let's get it together!
はい、せーの！アハ〜ン！
Okay, one, two! Ahan~
いいじゃん、いいじゃん！やだ〜！
That's good, that's good! Oh, stop it~
なんか普通にさ、みんなでわーっとした感じでさ、
はい！イェーイ！
Let's just do a normal, excited one together.
Okay! Yay!
ごらんとありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thanks for watching! Thank you very much!
水着といえばさ！
Speaking of swimsuits!
水着といえばさ！テンション上げ上げ！
Speaking of swimsuits! Get hyped up!
この水着衣装シャイニーウェーブver.来た！
私たちのも！
The Shiny Wave ver. swimsuit costumes are here!
Ours too!
え、今日販売されるんだって！
Eh, they're going on sale today!
ホロライブ・サマー2022グッズ
hololive Summer 2022 Goods
はい、そして出るんですか？はい、こちらなんと今日から受注販売開始！
Yes, and what's coming? Yes, these are actually starting pre-order today!
3Dアクリルスタンド！そしてランダム缶バッジ！
3D Acrylic Stands! And Random Tin Badges!
はい、プレミアムアクリルパネル！こちらの三種類の商品があるということで！イェーイ！
Yes, Premium Acrylic Panels! We have these three types of merchandise! Yay!
そしてそして、内容はこんな感じ！イェーイ！
And, here's what they look like! Yay!
アクリルスタンドはもうね、35種類あるんでね！
As for the Acrylic Stands, there are 35 different kinds!
ぜひゲットしてね！多いな！
Make sure to get them! That's a lot!
すごいそらちゃん！え、ポーズが...
Amazing, Sora-chan! Eh, the poses...
...おのおの決まってて良いですね！
...are uniquely decided for each one, it's great!
これみんながさ、だってさ、こういうポーズにしたいって潜在で撮ったのもさ！
This is because everyone took these promotional photos in the poses they wanted!
そうそうそう、撮った撮った！だから結構うちらですよ、これ！うちらですよ！
Right, right, we took them! So it's really us! It's us!
ねえ、やめなさい！何してんの？五期生の前出たら！五期生の前出てる、ほら！
Hey, stop it! What are you doing? Getting in front of Gen 5! Look, you're in front of Gen 5!
ねえ、五期生もちゃんと見て！ほら、ぽちぽちぽち！
どんなんやったんか？こんなんやった！
Hey, look at Gen 5 too! Look, clap clap clap!
What kind did we do? We did this kind!
こんなんやった！え、お前これ被るんだね？
We did this kind! Eh, you're drawing this, huh?
お前これ、後ろ...後ろから見るべき！見るべき！ハイハイハイ！
You should... you should look at this from behind! From behind! Yes, yes, yes!
え、そしてもう一つ！はい、ランダム缶バッジですね！
And, one more thing! Yes, it's the random tin badges!
これもヤバイね！こちらも35種類あるということで、すごいね！
These are crazy too! These also have 35 types, amazing!
ヤバイ！各世代どぼんとあります！
Insane! All generations are lumped together!
すごい！痛バッジ作れちゃうぜ、痛バッジ！
Amazing! You can make an ita-bag, an ita-bag!
カバンに貼ろう！カバンに貼ろう！
Put them on your bag! Put them on your bag!
そしてそして、なんとこちら！デデン！
And, and, how about this! Ta-da!
プレミアムアクリルパネル！プレミアムアクリルパネル！
Premium Acrylic Panels! Premium Acrylic Panels!
これはですね、全員集合しているプレミアムアクリルパネルこちらなんですけれども...
This is the Premium Acrylic Panel featuring everyone together...
...こちらのみ、本日から9月14日まで受注生産となっておりますので、ぜひこのタイミングで手に入れてください！
...only this one is made-to-order until September 14th, so please get it while you can!
これは受注生産だから気をつけるんだぞ！はい、気をつけてね！
This is made-to-order, so be careful! Yes, be careful!
気をつけて！最後読んで、ねね！あ、はい！
Be careful! Read the last part, Nene! Ah, okay!
詳細は概要欄にあるホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップをチェックしてください！
Check the hololive Production Official Shop linked in the description for details!
わかった！はい、丁寧丁寧に！チェックチェック！
Understood! Yes, very politely! Check check!
そして次の曲に行かないと間に合いません！ヤバイ、ヤバイ！行くぞ！
And if we don't go to the next song, we won't make it! Oh no! Let's go!
次の曲へ！イェーイ！千載一遇のものは、こちら！
To the next song! Yay! This once-in-a-lifetime piece is next!
夢見る空へ
To the Dreaming Sky
重ねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Never letting go of our joined hands
行くよ 行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go, to the dreaming sky
窓越しに見上げたとても小さな空
The tiny sky I looked up at through the window
ここで出会えたのは数えきれない奇跡
Meeting here was an uncountable miracle
繰り返した一歩が煌めきを繋いで
The repeated steps connect the sparkles
弾むような笑顔水色さ
A bouncing smile, the color of water
Step by step みんなの声が力になる
Step by step, everyone's voices become strength
Step by step ここでそれぞれ目指すもの
Step by step, what each of us aims for here
それぞれ描くもの...
What each of us draws...
...それぞれ願った夢へ
...towards the dreams each of us wished for
重ねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Never letting go of our joined hands
一人一人違う色で描き出すときめき
Each of us painting our excitement in different colors
振り向くことなく真っ直ぐに
Looking straight ahead without turning back
いくよ いこう 夢見る空へ
Here we go, let's head to the sky of our dreams
笑いあったことや
The times we laughed together
泣き出しそうになった日
And the days we felt like crying
思い出いっぱいなのに
Though we have so many memories
あっという間の日々
The days have passed by in a flash
上書きじゃなくて
Instead of overwriting them
名前つけて保存
I'll 'save as' and name them all
どれも全部大事な宝物
Each and every one is a precious treasure
One for all... 誰かのためが力になる
One for all... doing it for someone else gives me strength
All for one... 今日も賑やかすぎるくらい
All for one... today is almost too lively again
笑顔がもう止まらない
I can't stop smiling anymore
想いは膨らんでいく
These feelings keep growing
重ねた今ぎゅっと噛み締めた
Savoring this moment we've shared
一人一人違う声で歌声は広がる
With each of our unique voices, our song spreads far and wide
風を感じたら真っ直ぐに
Once you feel the breeze, look straight ahead
いくよ いこう 夢見る空へ
Here we go, let's head to the sky of our dreams
憧れ 手を伸ばした
I reached out towards my longing
掴み取ったその光が
The light that I've grasped
いつの日か
Will someday
また誰かの憧れに変わる
Become what someone else longs for
繋げよう
Let's pass it on
重ねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Never letting go of our joined hands
一人一人違う色で描き出すときめき
Each of us painting our excitement in different colors
出会った全てにありがとう
Thank you for everything we've encountered
奇跡だって起こし続けるよ
We'll keep on making miracles happen
ずっと
Always
そこにいて
Be right there
いくよ いこう 夢見る空へ
Here we go, let's head to the sky of our dreams
あすいろClearSky
Asuiro ClearSky
いつの間にか見つけてた 遠い夢
Before I knew it, I'd found a distant dream
一人じゃ見えなかった景色
A scenery I couldn't have seen alone
波打つ風の音 加速していく想いに
The sound of the surging wind, with accelerating feelings
戸惑いも覚えた
I even felt some bewilderment
追いかけた理想の姿は
The ideal image I chased after
まだ届かなくて遠いけど
Is still out of reach and far away, but...
きっとこの瞬間を かけがえない皆で
Surely, in this irreplaceable moment with everyone
共に行くよ 手を繋いで
We'll go together, hand in hand
宇宙は輝き宿して
The universe holds a brilliance
夢の場所へ
Toward the place of our dreams
駆け抜けていく僕たちの 青春の光は
Running through, the light of our youth
誰にも止められないよ
Can't be stopped by anyone
笑いあう未来 優しくこぼれる涙さえ
A future where we laugh, even the tears that softly fall
いまほら 輝かせて明日へ運ぶから
Look, now I'll make them shine and carry them to tomorrow
君の隣へ 僕たちは世界を越えていく
To your side, we'll cross over the world
迎えに行くよ
I'm coming to get you
まだ見えない明日も きらめきに変えてきっと
Surely, changing even the unseen tomorrow into a sparkle
僕たちが未来へと
Because we'll take you
連れて行くから
To the future
背伸びしては手を伸ばす 憧れの
Standing on tiptoe and reaching out toward my longing
行き先示す星になれ
Become the star that shows the way
つまずくその度 手を差し伸べ合えたなら
If we can reach out our hands to each other every time we stumble
すぐに届くはず
We should reach it soon
...さあ
...Come on.
そっと踏み出した
I took a gentle step forward
小さな勇気が
and this small bit of courage,
もう消えないように
so that it won't ever fade away,
繋げよう
let's connect it all.
不安も愛おしさも
Both our anxieties and our affection,
大切に抱きしめて
let's hold them close to our hearts
灯り行くよ
as we light the way forward.
目を合わせて
Lock eyes with each other.
3 2 1
晴れ渡る希望へ
Towards a clear-skied hope,
飛び出せるよ
we can leap out.
突き抜けて行く
We'll keep pushing through.
僕たちの透き通る決意は
Our transparent determination
まだまだ止められないよ
still cannot be stopped.
ありきたりな今日こそ
Even an ordinary day like today,
ときめきに変えてまた
let's turn it into excitement again.
僕たちがいつまでも背中押すから
Because we'll always be here to support you.
ずっと一人で描いてた
I'd been drawing it all alone,
キャンバスがいつか重なって糸になって
but the canvases eventually overlapped and became a thread.
また少しずつ芽生える大好きを紡ぎ
And little by little, we'll weave the love that starts to sprout.
どこまでも高く
Higher and higher,
あすいろの空へ
into the sky of tomorrow's color.
駆け抜けて行く
We'll go racing through.
僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth
誰にも止められないよ
cannot be stopped by anyone.
笑い合う度優しくこぼれる涙さえ
Every time we laugh together, even the tears that softly spill,
今ほら輝かせ明日へ運ぶから
look, they'll shine and carry us into tomorrow.
君の隣へ
To your side.
僕たちは世界を越えて行く
We will transcend the world.
迎えに行くよ
We're coming to get you.
まだ見えない明日も煌めきに変えてきっと
Even the unseen tomorrow, we'll surely turn into a sparkle.
僕たちが未来へと
As we head into the future...
果てのない未来へと
Into an endless future...
連れて行くから
...we'll take you there.
地平線を水平線にしたら
If we turn the horizon into a sea-level line,
らーSea らーSea らーSea-Sea!
Ra-Sea ra-Sea ra-Sea-Sea!
WAHHHHH!!!
浸食! Sing! Shock! 浸食! Sing! Shock!
Invasion! Sing! Shock! Invasion! Sing! Shock!
海流でみんなに HELLO HELLO
Saying HELLO HELLO to everyone via the currents!
浸食! Sing! Shock! 浸食! Sing! Shock!
Invasion! Sing! Shock! Invasion! Sing! Shock!
深水 深海 Swing & Sweet
Deep water, deep sea, Swing & Sweet!
ふー!
Phew!
高い 名誉 清楚の称号 4人でかっさらっちゃったろ
High honor, the title of 'pure', the four of us snatched it all!
さあさあさあ さあさあさあ
Now, now, now! Now, now, now!
地球を侵略 TAKODAのCHに登場
Invading the Earth, appearing on TAKODA's channel!
いないないなー いないなー
Now you see us, now you don't!
えっこれで海賊本職化!? 鮫コスプレってことじゃん!
Wait, does this make piracy our full-time job?! It's just a shark cosplay!
キミたちも本物の味 知りたいのね?
You guys want to know the taste of the real thing too, right?
Shrimp, と salmon, サメぜんぶ食べます
Shrimp and salmon, the shark eats it all!
(eat shrimp... we eat every single shrimp on the earth... oh mic's on!)
全人類乗船 母なる海へと
All of humanity on board, head to the mother sea!
水に落とされて... 最高のDeep blue
Dropped into the water... into the ultimate Deep Blue!
私(あてぃし)達の海へご招待
We invite you to our ocean!
(Our showtime!!)
そんじゃ
Well then!
(1) Depart the harbor
(2) Launch our marine jet
(3) Start a sharkventure
(4) And TAKO-over the world with sea
Here we go / いっせーの
Here we go / All together now!
はい はい はい
Hai! Hai! Hai!
おーしゃん おーしゃん Lovely ocean
Ocean! Ocean! Lovely Ocean!
みちびいた新世界
Leading us to a brand new world!
青い星をウルトラマリンに染めて
Dyeing the blue planet in ultramarine!
いぇー いぇー いぇー!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
おーしゃん おーしゃん Epic ocean
Ocean! Ocean! Epic Ocean!
全域全おーしゃん 止まらないかい
The entire area is an ocean! Can't stop us now, can you?
AQUA 満杯 Blueat Planetへ進め
Filled with AQUA! Head towards the Blueat Planet!
ヨーソロー ヨーソロー! (よっしゃー!)
Yousoro! Yousoro! (Alright!)
この星を一雫にしたら
If we turn this planet into a single drop,
らーSea らーSea らーSea-Sea! WAHHHH!!!
Ra-Sea ra-Sea ra-Sea-Sea! WAHHHH!!!
続いては新曲！
Next up is a new song!
『りゅーーっときてきゅーーっ！！！』
"Ryooo-to Kite Kyooo!!!"
はい、はい！
Hai, hai!
おー、みんな盛り上がってるかーい！
Oh, is everyone getting excited?!
りゅーーっときてきゅーっ
Ryooo-to kite kyooo!
大地も大海も巻き込んで大波乱～！？
Engulfing both the land and the vast sea in a great upheaval!?
(WE ARE UMISEA!! UMISEA.JP!!)
ぎゅーっとして ちゅーっとして りゅーっときてきゅーっ！！！！
Hold me tight, give me a kiss, and ryooo-to kite kyooo!!!!
ぱっぱっぱ やっぱっぱ ぱっぱっ しゅいふっく
Pa pa pa ya pa pa pa pa shuifukku!
ぱっぱっぱ やっぱっぱ ぱっぱっ パラダイス
Pa pa pa ya pa pa pa pa paradise!
ぱや ぱや ぱや ぱや
Paya paya paya paya!
あらくれ海に浸食船
An invasion ship in the rough seas!
大波 小波で 水の中 (ありゃ〜)
Big waves, small waves, inside the water (Whoops~)
なんやかやんで サメとタコ どっかにさらわれて
Somehow or another, the shark and octopus were carried off somewhere!
行方不明
Now missing in action!
Missing
じゃあ冒険しようよ！(いぇーい！)
Then let's go on an adventure! (Yay!)
なんくる探検だ！(いぇーい！)
It's a nankuru exploration! (Yay!)
遭難しても すぐ満々腹 (ばくばくばく〜ん♪)
Even if we're shipwrecked, we'll soon have full bellies (Baku-baku-bakoon~♪)
クルーの皆さん 宝物 探索 準備はいーい？？
Crew members! Are you ready for some treasure hunting??
1!! セクシー船長
1!! Sexy Captain
2!! 清楚メイド
2!! Neat and tidy Maid
3!! 掃除屋インターン
3!! Cleaning Intern
あくまりさかまた おーおーしゃん
Akuma-ri-Sakamata, O-O-Ocean
りゅーっときてきゅーっ (りゅーっときてきゅーっ!!)
Ryuu---tto Kite Kyuu---!!! (Ryuu---tto Kite Kyuu---!!!)
アクア的神秘 深海は銀河のサブマリン
Aqua-style mystery, the deep sea is a galactic submarine
暗黒のブラックホールへダイブ
Dive into the dark black hole
りゅーっときてきゅーっ (りゅーっときてきゅーっ!!)
Ryuu---tto Kite Kyuu---!!! (Ryuu---tto Kite Kyuu---!!!)
楽園アドベンチャー 我ら我らトレジャーハンター
Paradise adventure, we are the treasure hunters
難解な地図の謎も
Even the riddles of a complex map
(リカ、リカ) ポカンとうまくても
(Rika, Rika) Even if we are spaced out
(いただきまーす)
(Itadakimasu)
曖昧な航海図で
With an ambiguous nautical chart
(よーそろー) 全速力で出帆して
(Steady as she goes) Setting sail at full speed
(WE ARE UMISEA!! UMISEA!! UMISEA JP!!)
ぎゅっとしてちゅっとして りゅーっときてきゅーっ!!!
Give me a hug, give me a kiss, and Ryuu---tto Kite Kyuu---!!!
はい！ということで、Climax Story Live 特別コラボ、UmiSeaとUMISEA JPによるUmiSeaメドレーでした！イエーイ！
Alright! That was the Climax Story Live special collaboration, the UmiSea Medley by UmiSea and UMISEA JP! Yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい。みんなね、もうグラとイナニスの登場で盛り上がってるかと思いますが、ま、順番にね、自己紹介していきましょう。
Yes. I'm sure everyone is pumped after Gura and Ina'nis showed up, so let's introduce ourselves in order.
ま、まずね、じゃあ船長からいきます。
Well, first, the Captain will go.
アホイ！ホロライブ3期生、宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンです！君たち楽しんでるか！？
Ahoy! Hololive 3rd Gen, Captain of the Houshou Pirates, Houshou Marine here! Are you guys having fun!?
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい、次あくたんどうぞー。
Okay, next, Akutan, please.
はーい！皆さんどうもこんあくあー！ホロライブ2期生、湊あくあです！こんにちは！
Hello! Hello everyone, Kon-Aqua! Hololive 2nd Gen, Minato Aqua here! Hello!
イエーイ！次！
Yay! Next!
バクバクバク〜ン！秘密結社holoXの掃除屋インターン、沙花叉クロヱでーす！君たちに見えてるか！？
Baku-baku-bakoon! Secret Society holoX's cleaning intern, Sakamata Chloe! Can you guys see me!?
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい、おはこんにちこんばんは！ホロライブEnglish -Myth-の一伊那尓栖です！よろしくお願いします！イエーイ！
Yes, hello everyone! I'm Ninomae Ina'nis of Hololive English -Myth-! Please treat me well! Yay!
イエーイ！イナ！
Yay! Ina!
ハロードーモ、シャークです！ホロライブEnglish -Myth-の、がうる・ぐらです！
Hello, it's the shark! Gawr Gura of Hololive English -Myth-!
イエーイ！ぐらちゃん！
Yay! Gura-chan!
はい、じゃあ何でこの5人なの？っていう人もいると思うんだよね。船長が説明してあげようかな。
Now, I think some people might be wondering why it's these five. I'll explain.
確かになー。ENの2人がゲストで来てくれたのマジびっくりしてる人もいるかもね。
True. Some people might be really surprised that the two from EN came as guests.
ねー。さっき歌ったのはですね、UmiSeaメドレーということでね、君たち覚えてるかなー。前半の曲は去年の夏にリリースされた「浸食!!地球全域全おーしゃん」！
Yeah. We just sang the UmiSea Medley, do you guys remember? The first song was 'Shinshoku!! Chikyuu Zeniki O-O-Ocean!!' released last summer!
やっぱ夏といえばね、私たちUmiSeaでしょ！っていうことでね。
Speaking of summer, it has to be us, UmiSea!
ええ、ENの2人にも特別ゲストとして出演してもらったわけです。ねー。
Exactly, so we had the two from EN appear as special guests as well.
イエーイ！サンキュー！
Yay! Thank you!
ああ、こちらこそ誘ってくれてありがとうございます。いや、去年のテンションも高かったと思ったんですが、
Ah, thank you for inviting us. I thought last year's energy was high,
今年はライブでみんなのダンスもあり、なんかレベルアップした感じですね。
but this year with everyone dancing, it feels like we've leveled up.
そして、やっと、やっとみんなと同じステージで3Dで歌えて、本当に嬉しいです。サンキュー！
And finally, finally, I'm so happy we could sing on the same stage together in 3D. Thank you!
イエーイ！サンキュー！
Yay! Thank you!
私も嬉しいです！かわいい！宝鐘先輩、マリン先輩、ありがとうございます！
I'm happy too! So cute! Houshou-senpai, Marine-senpai, thank you very much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして、ウェルカム、クロヱ！沙花叉先輩、真の家族になりましたね。
And, welcome Chloe! Sakamata-senpai, we've become a real family now.
イエーイ！
Yay!
そして、この大きいステージで歌える…堂々、UmiSeaの結成からも一年が経ったことが信じられない。
And being able to sing on this big stage... I can't believe it's been a year since UmiSea's formation.
Happy Birthday to UmiSea！この音楽は世界中のすべての海岸まで届く！
Happy Birthday to UmiSea! This music will reach every coast in the world!
グッド・ジャパニーズ！うんうん。
Good Japanese! Mm-hm.
ありがとうございます！ということでね、えー後半歌った曲「りゅーっときてきゅー」は29日0時より配信がスタートしております！
Thank you! So, the second song we sang, 'Ryuu---tto Kite Kyuu---!!!', is available for streaming starting from midnight on the 29th!
みんな聞いてくれたかなー？うんうん。
Did everyone listen to it? Mm-hm.
「りゅーっときてきゅー」からは沙花叉も仲間に加わっております！沙花叉、どうでしたか？
Sakamata also joined as a member starting from 'Ryuu---tto Kite Kyuu---!!!'! Sakamata, how was it?
沙花叉が初参戦した「りゅーっときてきゅー」はセリフパートがめちゃ早口だったので、噛みまくって大変でしたー。
The spoken part of 'Ryuu---tto Kite Kyuu---!!!', which I joined for the first time, was so fast that I kept tripping over my words.
でも、おーしゃんの時に好きだった先輩たちのわちゃわちゃした掛け合いを、沙花叉も一緒にできて楽しかったです！
But I had so much fun being able to join in on the chaotic banter with my senpais that I loved in the O-O-Ocean era!
はい、じゃあ沙花叉もね、加わったことで5人になりましたね！ということで！念願のポーズができますと！
Alright, so with Sakamata joining, we're now five! That means we can finally do our long-awaited pose!
じゃあみんな、配置についてください。グラ、イナ、Ready to pose? Let's go!
Everyone, get in position. Gura, Ina, ready to pose? Let's go!
ハイ、チーズ！
Say cheese!
あ、ちょっと、ぐらセンター、ぐらセンター！
Ah, wait, Gura in the center, Gura in the center!
はい、ぐらセンターで...
Okay, Gura in the center...
はい、船長ちょっと右左、右左...
Okay, Captain, move a bit right and left, right and left...
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
ヒトデ、ヒトデのポーズ！
Starfish, the starfish pose!
さ、はい。さてそろそろ時間となってきましたので、次の曲に行きましょうか。
Alright, yes. Now that it's about that time, shall we move on to the next song?
ぐら、一伊那尓栖さん、今日は本当に駆けつけてくれてありがとう！
Gura, Ina'nis-san, thank you so much for rushing over today!
イェーイ！楽しかったね！
Yay! It was fun!
楽しかったです！ありがとうございます！
It was fun! Thank you so much!
はい。これからはね、この5人で毎年夏と海を盛り上げていければと思いますからね！
Yes. From now on, I hope the five of us can liven up the summer and the sea every year!
じゃあ元気よく次の曲振りしましょうか。
Then, let's introduce the next song with lots of energy.
せーのでいきましょうか。
Let's do it on three.
じゃあぐら、ぐらいってみようか！
Alright Gura, Gura, give it a go!
わかりました！おー！
Understood! Oh!
それでは、続いての曲は...
Well then, the next song is...
こちらー！
This one!
そうさ ずっと 僕らの軌跡が
That's right, may our path forever
途切れないように 歌うんだ
Continue on, as we sing
もっと 高く 大きな声で
Higher and with a louder voice
Prism Melody
作詞・作曲・編曲：5u5h1
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: 5u5h1
秘めてた 何かが 始まるサイン
A hidden sign that something is starting
集まって 気付けば 鼓動を 奏でた
We gathered and before we knew it, played a heartbeat
夢に見る だけじゃ もう 足りないでしょ
Just dreaming isn't enough anymore, is it?
日々を 待ってる 世界が あるよ
There's a world waiting for our days
楽しい 予感に ほら
Look, with a fun premonition
飛び乗れば いい
You just have to jump on
ときめきは 止められないから 走ろう
This excitement can't be stopped, so let's run
連れて行くよ 光の真ん中
I'll take you to the center of the light
夢の 先へ 羽ばたける
Where we can fly beyond our dreams
勇気は 君の 願い
Our courage is your wish
みんなで 繋いだ この奇跡が
May this miracle we all connected
途切れないように 歌うんだ
Continue on, as we sing
もっと 高く 大きな声で
Higher and with a louder voice
答えとか 理屈に 惑わされて
Led astray by answers and logic
彷徨っても 戻れる この場所が あったんだ
Even if we wander, we had this place to return to
地図にない 道行く 僕らの 旅
Our journey on a path not found on any map
願いだけが 道標だよ
Only our wishes are our guide
夢の色が 変わっても
Even if the color of our dreams changes
変わらない メロディ
This melody remains the same
君のために 僕らのために 歌おう
For you, and for us, let's sing
そうさ 君と 僕らの軌跡は
That's right, the path for you and us
終わらないよ 涙さえ
Will never end, we'll turn even tears
きっかけに 変えていこう
Into an opportunity to move forward
信じてくれる 仲間と一緒に
Together with friends who believe in us
どこへだって 飛び出して行こう
Let's leap out to anywhere we want
もっと 遠く 空を 越えて
Further away, beyond the sky
未来の 僕らに まだ見ぬ 君に
To our future selves, and to you whom we've yet to see
伝えたいこと たくさん あるんだ
There's so much we want to tell you
向かい風 今は 当たり前なんかじゃない
The headwind, now it's not something to take for granted
翼を 広げて さあ 今 飛ぼう
Spread your wings and let's fly now
Take my hand
連れて行くよ 光の真ん中
I'll take you to the center of the light
夢の 先へ 羽ばたける
Where we can fly beyond our dreams
勇気は 君の 願い
Our courage is your wish
みんなで 繋いだ この奇跡が
May this miracle we all connected
途切れないように 歌うんだ
Continue on, as we sing
もっと 高く 大きな声で
Higher and with a louder voice
…らの未来 彩って
...the colors of our future,
どこまでも響け プリズムメロディ
Resonate forever, Prism Melody
ホロメン音頭
Holomen Ondo
ちょいとそこ行く皆々様よ！
Hey you all passing by there!
僕らと一緒に踊らない？
Won't you dance with us?
さあ、お手を拝借！
Now, everyone clap along!
パパパン パパパン ハイ！
Clap, clap, clap! Clap, clap, clap! Hey!
ちょうちん灯れば 笑顔が集う
When the lanterns light up, smiles gather
ホロメン音頭（あーよいしょ）
Holomen Ondo (A-yoisho!)
うちわ 綿あめ かき氷だね
Paper fans, cotton candy, and shaved ice
パーリラ パーリラ わんこも踊る（そーれ）
Pa-ri-ra, pa-ri-ra! Even the doggies are dancing (Heave-ho!)
みんな揃って どどんがどん
Everyone together, do-don-ga-don
まつり囃子だ どどんがどん
It's the festival music, do-don-ga-don
（よいしょ はーどっこい）
(Yoisho! Ha-dokkoi!)
あかね ぐちなし わかなえ しおん
Madder, gardenia, young seedlings, and aster
ホロメン音頭（あーよいしょ）
Holomen Ondo (A-yoisho!)
浴衣 あざやか 花吹雪だね
Vibrant yukatas, like a blizzard of petals
パーリラ パーリラ 金魚も踊る（そーれ）
Pa-ri-ra, pa-ri-ra! Even the goldfish are dancing (Heave-ho!)
みんな揃って どどんがどん
Everyone together, do-don-ga-don
まつり囃子だ どどんがどん
It's the festival music, do-don-ga-don
ホロメンを集めて囃し 保護者かな
Gathering Holomen and cheering them on, am I their guardian?
推しの言葉だ 満ちる幸せ
It's the words of my oshi, filling me with happiness
「さぁさぁ皆さん、音頭を踊れば温度が上がる！
"Now everyone, if we dance the ondo, the temperature will rise!
赤ん坊から利かん坊まで、誰でもいらっしゃーい！」
From babies to naughty kids, everyone's welcome!"
「あー、こまけぇこたぁいいんだよ！今宵の祭、シャル・ウィ・ダンス？
"Ah, don't sweat the small stuff! Tonight's festival, shall we dance?
踊り踊らば はっぴぃっぴー！」
If we dance, we'll be happy-ppy!"
ヨイヨイ宵の口 西明かりはるか
The early evening, with the western light far off
ホロメン音頭（あーよいしょ）
Holomen Ondo (A-yoisho!)
光さんざめく 天の川だね
The sparkling Milky Way
パーリラ パーリラ ばあばも踊る（そーれ）
Pa-ri-ra, pa-ri-ra! Even grandmas are dancing (Heave-ho!)
みんな揃って どどんがどん
Everyone together, do-don-ga-don
待って待って待って！早速、まずは自己紹介からしていきたいと思います！
Wait, wait, wait! First, we'd like to introduce ourselves!
はい！行きます！ホロライブ所属大空スバルです！よろしくお願いします！
Alright, here I go! I'm Hololive's Oozora Subaru! Nice to meet you!
そして！
And!
はい！ホロライブゲーマーズ、戌神ころねー！ゆびゆびー！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Hololive Gamers' Inugami Korone! Yubi yubi! Nice to meet you!
そして、からのー？
And after that...?
刮目せよ！Yes My Dark！吾輩の名前は、ラプラス・ダークネスだ！
Witness me! Yes My Dark! My name is La+ Darknesss!
おい！ヤマダ！ヤマダ！
Hey! Yamada! Yamada!
はい！ゆびゆび！刮目せよ！えー、常闇トワ様でーす！イエーイ！
Hi! Yubi yubi! Witness me! Uh, I'm Tokoyami Towa-sama! Yay!
詰め合わせじゃん！
That was a total mix!
はい、詰め合わせで行きましたところで。ということでですね、以上のメンバーでホロライブサマー2022の新曲、『ホロメン音頭』お送りしました！
Alright, now that we've mixed it up. With these members, we performed the new Hololive Summer 2022 song, "Holomen Ondo"!
いやー、なんか今までに無かったそういう曲だったから、すごい新鮮だったよね！
Man, that was such a fresh song, unlike anything we've had before!
しかもー！なんとこの曲を公式ショップで買うと、あ、なんと！お祭りで使えるんだぞ、みんなのー！
Plus! If you buy this song from the official shop, you can use it for festivals, everyone!
ラプちゃん読めたねー！
Lap-chan, you could read that!
まあ、今年はもう遅いから、来年とかに使ってもらえたらなと思います！
Well, it's too late for this year, so I hope you use it next year!
はい、ということでですね、詳しくはホロライブサマー2022の公式サイトから確認してみてください。お願いします！
So, please check the Hololive Summer 2022 official site for details. Thank you!
お！で、せっかくだから、なんと浴衣なので、せっかくだからスクショを撮ろう！
Oh! And since we're in yukatas, let's take a screenshot!
それでは、じゃあYes My Dark決めちゃいます！あ、じゃあラプちゃん動けて！
Alright, let's do the "Yes My Dark" pose! Lap-chan, get ready!
行くよー、ラプちゃん号令かけてー
Here we go, Lap-chan, give us the signal.
せーの！刮目せよ！
One, two! Witness me!
あ、もう一回いいか、乗り遅れた
Oh, one more time? I missed it.
せーの！刮目せよ！Yes My Dark！
One, two! Witness me! Yes My Dark!
まあでも絶対浴衣でするポーズじゃなくてちょっと草ｗ
But it's funny because it's definitely not a pose for yukatas lol.
はい！ということでですね、えー、なんとちょっと早いんですけど、次がね、最後の曲みたいです。
Alright! So, it's a bit early, but it seems the next one is the final song.
まあでもね、ちょっと名残惜しいんですけど。でも最後はやっぱりね、あのホロライブサマー2022の3つ目の新曲で終わるみたいですよ。
I know, it's a bit sad. But we'll finish with the third new song from Hololive Summer 2022.
ちなみに、この曲が終わった後、皆さん帰らないでください！
By the way, everyone, please don't leave after this song!
うぇい！なんかすごいサプライズが待ってるみたいですね！
Yeah! Looks like a huge surprise is waiting!
知ってたんかー！
You knew?!
はい、ということでね、みんな気になってると思うので、早速次の曲に行っちゃいましょう！
Alright, everyone must be curious, so let's get right to the next song!
クライマックスストーリーライブのトリを飾る曲は...！
The song to close out the Climax Story Live is...!
せーの！こちらー！
One, two! This one!
夏が何度も巡り来ても　忘れないでいたい　ずっと
No matter how many summers come and go, I want to remember forever.
少し寂しいと思ったんだ
I thought it felt a bit lonely.
浴衣の袖を揺らす
The sleeves of my yukata flutter.
「風が涼しいね」なんて言った
"The breeze is cool, isn't it?" you said.
君の表情見つけたせいかな
Was it because I caught a glimpse of your expression?
日が暮れるまではしゃいで笑ってると
We were frolicking and laughing until the sun went down.
オレンジが縁取ったシルエット
The orange light outlined our silhouettes.
蝉の残り声や　波のざわめき
The lingering cries of cicadas and the rustling of waves.
遠くなっていくたびに　きっと　思い出せる
Every time they fade into the distance, I'm sure I'll remember.
祭りの夜の空を見ると
When I look at the sky on a festival night...
まるで思い出の数だけ
...it's as if there are as many memories...
色が光っているみたいだね
...as there are shining colors.
一つ一つ　綺麗に
One by one, beautifully...
咲いて　咲いて
Blooming, blooming...
いくよ
...they go.
新しい浴衣着替えて
Changing into a new yukata
「どうかな？」って見せ合ったり
Showing each other and asking "How do I look?"
気温のせいにしちゃって
Blaming it on the temperature
熱い気持ちで未来を語ったり
Talking about the future with passion
どんなことでも　冒険みたいになる
Anything can become an adventure
期待値が上がってしまうシーズン
The season when expectations rise
当たり前の日も　特別だってこと
That even ordinary days are special
この瞬間　この一瞬だって
That even this moment, this very instant
思わせる
Makes us feel that way
賑わう人で混み合うほど
The more crowded it gets with people
なぜだか楽しい気分だね
The more fun it feels for some reason
映画の窓のような屋台
Stalls like windows in a movie
ひとつひとつ覗いて
Looking into each and every one
一緒に　一緒に　歩こう
Let's walk together, together
振り返っても
Even if I look back
ほんのちょっとも
Not even a little bit
トリミング出来ないようなシーンばっかり
There are only scenes that can't be trimmed
過ぎ去ってしまう前にもう一度だけ
Just once more before it passes by
みんなといたい
I want to be with everyone
想い出たちを彩るように
To color our memories
夜空に咲いた花火が
The fireworks blooming in the night sky
色鮮やかに輝いてた
Were shining vividly
ずっと…一緒にいたいよ
I want to be with you... forever
来年もまたこんな風に
Next year, in this same way again
笑い合いたいって思うから
Because I want us to laugh together
線香花火に願うんだ
I make a wish on a sparkler
「ずっとずっと続いて」
"Let it last forever and ever"
きっと　きっと
Surely, surely
叶う
It will come true
お、ライブ無事終わった？
Oh, is the live over safely?
よしよし、今のうちにクリスタルをっと…
Good, good, while I can, I'll take the crystals...
あっはっは。これで来年のサマーも…
Ahahaha. With this, next year's Summer will also...
あれ、マリンさん。もうライブは終わりましたよ。
Oh, Marine-san. The live is already over, you know.
えっ！？
What!?
あ、これ、その…
Ah, this is, well...
あぁ〜〜！
Aaa~~!
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future
あの夢手にした
I held that dream in my hands
それぞれ誓った　ここで
Each of us made a vow, right here
走り出そう
Let's start running
どこ見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
It had sprouted in a place that was pitch black no matter where I looked
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
My eyes were captivated by just a tiny bit of hope
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my heart that's swaying with anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I was squeezing out just a tiny bit of courage
諦めの文字でリミットして進む
Moving forward by limiting myself with the word "giving up"
苦しい時も
Even during painful times
もう私は
I am no longer
独りじゃないから
alone anymore
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
This excitement won't stop
騒ごう
Let's make some noise
超えて...
Go beyond...
世界に見せてあげる
We'll show the world
アクセル踏んでみたい
I want to step on the gas
後悔なんてさせない
We won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ違った
With our each unique...
鼓動で
...heartbeats,
走れ GO!
Run now, GO!
ホロライブ・サマー2022に
ご参加ありがとうございました！
Thank you for participating in
Hololive Summer 2022!